// below is the array that holds all the quiz questions
// questions are taken off of https://www.tutorialspoint.com/javascript/ and https://www.topzenith.com/2020/04/javascript-quiz-with-questions-and-answers.html
var quizQuestions = [{
    question: "Which built-in method adds one or more elements to the end of an array and returns the new length of the array?",
    pickA: "last()",
    pickB: "put()",
    pickC: "push()",
    pickD: "none of the above",
    answer: "pickC"},
{
    question: "Which built-in method returns the string representation of the number's value?",
    pickA: "toValue()",
    pickB: "toNumber()",
    pickC: "toString()",
    pickD: "none of the above",
    answer: "pickC"},
{
    question: "Which of the following function of String object extracts a section of a string and returns a new string?",
    pickA: "slice()",
    pickB: "split()",
    pickC: "replace()",
    pickD: "search()",
    answer: "pickA"},
    {
    question: "Which of the following function of String object returns the calling string value converted to upper case?",
    pickA: "toLocaleUpperCase()",
    pickB: "toUpperCase()",
    pickC: "toString()",
    pickD: "substring()",
    answer: "pickB"},
    /*{
    question: "Which of the following function of Array object returns the first (least) index of an element within the array equal to the specified value, or -1 if none is found?",
    pickA: "indexOf()",
    pickB: "join()",
    pickC: "lastIndexOf()",
    pickD: "map()",
    answer: "pickA"},
    {
    question: "Which of the following function of Array object adds and/or removes elements from an array?",
    pickA: "toSource()",
    pickB: "sort()",
    pickC: "upshift()",
    pickD: "splice()",
    answer: "pickD"},
    {
    question: "What is the HTML tag under which one can write javaScript code?",
    pickA: "<javascript>...</javascript>",
    pickB: "<script>...</script>",
    pickC: "<scripted>...</scripted>",
    pickD: "<js>...</js>",
    answer: "pickB"},
    {
    question: "Which of the following is the correct syntax to display 'purduesports.com' in an alert box?",
    pickA: "alertbox('purduesports.com')",
    pickB: "msgbox('purduesports.com')",
    pickC: "alert('purduesports.com')",
    pickD: "msg('purduesports.com')",
    answer: "pickC"},
    {
    question: "What is the difference between '==' and '==='?",
    pickA: "Both B & C",
    pickB: "Both operators are the same",
    pickC: "'==' checks only for equality in value whereas '===' is a strictre equality test",
    pickD: "None of the above",
    answer: "pickC"},
    {
    question: "What is the output of below? 33 == 33.0",
    pickA: "True",
    pickB: "33",
    pickC: "False",
    pickD: "None of the above",
    answer: "pickA"},
    {
    question: "Javascript is ______________ language.",
    pickA: "an interpreted",
    pickB: "a compiled",
    pickC: "a translated",
    pickD: "none of the above",
    answer: "pickA"},
    {
    question: "What is the correct file extension for javaScript files?",
    pickA: ".java",
    pickB: ".js",
    pickC: ".javascript",
    pickD: ".script",
    answer: "pickB"},    
    {
    question: "What label catches all values except those specified?",
    pickA: "otherwise",
    pickB: "default",
    pickC: "any",
    pickD: "all",
    answer: "pickB"},
    {
    question: "Which of the following is not a property of the window object?",
    pickA: "document",
    pickB: "menu",
    pickC: "navigator",
    pickD: "history",
    answer: "pickB"},   
    {
    question: "Which of the followig is NOT a valid function call?",
    pickA: "var x=myfunc();",
    pickB: "myfunc();",
    pickC: "x=myfunc()",
    pickD: "myfunc",
    answer: "pickD"},   
    {
    question: "Which event is specific to the keyboard?",
    pickA: "onclick",
    pickB: "onkeyboardpress",
    pickC: "onfocus",
    pickD: "onkeydown",
    answer: "pickD"},
    {
    question: "To see if three variables are all equal we would use",
    pickA: "A=B=C",
    pickB: "(A==B) && (B==C)",
    pickC: "(A==B) & (B==C)",
    pickD: "(A=B) && (B=C)",
    answer: "pickB"},  
    {
    question: "Which event do you use to run something after the page has finished loading?",
    pickA: "onfinished",
    pickB: "unload",
    pickC: "onload",
    pickD: "oncomplete",
    answer: "pickC"}, 
    {
    question: "The code to obtain a random number between 5 and 9 inclusive is",
    pickA: "Math.floor((Math.random() * 5) + 4",
    pickB: "Math.floor((Math.random() * 4) + 4",
    pickC: "Math.floor((Math.random() * 4) + 4",
    pickD: "Math.floor((Math.random() * 5) + 5",
    answer: "pickD"}, 
    {
    question: "You define a method using",
    pickA: "obj.method",
    pickB: "obj.method[]",
    pickC: "obj.method()",
    pickD: "obj-method",
    answer: "pickC"}, */
];